<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" /><updated>2024-11-28T11:46:17-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/atom.xml</id><title type="html">Neen Bean Reflections</title><author><name>Jilleen Phillips</name></author><entry><title type="html">Write Early and Often When Doing Genealogy Research</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/11/27/write_early_and_often.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Write Early and Often When Doing Genealogy Research" /><published>2024-11-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-27T09:51:16-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/11/27/write_early_and_often</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/11/27/write_early_and_often.html"><![CDATA[<p>When you are doing genealogy research, one of the best tools you have at your disposal is <em>writing.</em></p>

<p>Even though “a soundly reasoned, coherently written conclusion” is the final step of the Genealogical Proof Standard, that doesn’t mean you have to wait until until your research is complete before you begin writing. In fact, it can be highly beneficial to begin writing as soon as possible.</p>

<p>Writing up hypotheses and proof discussions early in the research process can help you to build a map for continuing your research, help you to figure out where to look next. Writing while you are researching helps you to stay tightly focused on your very specific research goal, rather than just “gathering information.”</p>

<p>Writing early can also help narrow the focus of the inevitable learning that comes along with genealogy research, the meta research that has to be done in order to understand what you are finding. Rather than reading all of the books about the Civil War that you can find, perhaps you just need to seek out information about just one battle or one regiment that your ancestor participated in. Perhaps you need to learn about migration from Vermont into the southern tier of New York State because you find so many people seemed to have moved between those two specific areas, rather than reading about migration from New England further west. Or maybe your interest is in Washington county between the years of 1790 and 1820, rather than the whole history from when it was settled to today.</p>

<p>Writing can help you to study <em>why</em> you are pursuing the line of research that has your attention. Maybe in writing out your theory and detailing the evidence you have to prove it, you will find that your logic is flawed, or that there is significant contradictory evidence. You can also test your theory by turning it around and writing to <em>disprove</em> it.</p>

<p>Writing is thinking, so writing early in your research process can dramatically improve the efficiency of your research. Don’t save your best tool until all of the thinking is done!</p>]]></content><author><name>Jilleen Phillips</name></author><category term="genealogy, writing" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you are doing genealogy research, one of the best tools you have at your disposal is writing.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello World</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/11/26/hello_world.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello World" /><published>2024-11-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-26T09:51:16-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/11/26/hello_world</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/11/26/hello_world.html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello World! It’s very nice to meet you!</p>]]></content><author><name>Jilleen Phillips</name></author><category term="Misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World! It’s very nice to meet you!]]></summary></entry></feed>